我受够了  你每次都不敲门就闯进来
That is it! You just barge in here, you don't knock
-对不起  -你对别人的隐私毫无尊重
- I'm sorry. - You have no respect for anybody's privacy.
-慢着  慢着  -你才慢着  太过分了
- Wait! Wait! - You wait! This is riduculous!
-我能说一件事吗  -什么事
- Can I just say one thing? - What?!
这块布织的非常松  我仍能看见...
That's a relatively open weave that I can still see...
...你的胸脯
...your nippular areas.
亲爱的  给他们讲讲你的病人
Honey, tell them the story about your patient...
如何把一件事想成另一件事
...who thinks things are other things.
例如电话响时她就去洗澡
When the phone rings and she takes a shower.
差不多是那样
That's pretty much it.
-但你说得很好  亲爱的  -谢谢
- But you tell it really well, sweetie. - Thanks. Okay.
现在快走吧  好让我们谈谈你
Now go away so we can talk about you.
好吧  我会想念你的
Okay. I'll miss you.
-他很不错吧  -他好帅  也很喜欢你
- Isn't he great? - He's cute. He likes you so much.
我知道  他人很好  而且很复杂
I know. He's so sweet. And so complicated, you know?
算是心理医生中比较正常的了
And for a shrink, he's not too shrinky.
你们会在他沙发上做吗
Think you'll do it on his couch?
我不知道...那有点奇怪
I don't know. That's a little weird.
那是聚乙烯沙发
It's vinyl.
大家还想要点什么吗
Okay, you guys want anything else?
-我要...  -抱歉  卖完了  别人呢
- Could I have? - Sorry. We're out of those. Anybody else?
有什么我不知道吗
Did I miss something?
她还在因为我看见她的胸脯生气
No, she's still upset because I saw her boobies.
你看她的胸脯干吗
What were you doing seeing her boobies?
那是意外  我又不是隔条街
It was an accident. Not like I was across the street
边吃甜甜圈边用望远镜偷看
with a telescope and a box of donuts..
能换个话题吗
Can we change the subject, please?
没错  那不是她的胸脯  而是她的胸部
Hollo. These aren't her "boobies." These are her breasts.
菲比  我要的不只是改变字眼
Pheebs, I was hoping for more of a change.
你知道吗  我不知你为何这么尴尬
Y'know, I don't know why you're so embarrassed,
你的胸脯很好看
they were very nice boobies.
"好看"它们很"好看"
"Nice"? They were "nice"?
就这样  手套还能用好看形容呢
That's it? I mean, mittens are "nice."
我这里外不是人啊
Okay. Rock, hard place. Me.
你真逗
You're so funny!
他真的很逗
He's really funny.
他不开玩笑的时候我可不想待在这儿
I wouldn't wanna be there when the laughter stops.
等等  回去上句  机灵鬼
Whoa, back up there, sparky.
那是什么意思
What did you mean by that?
你似乎有亲密上的问题
It seems that maybe you have intimacy issues...
你用你的幽默和人保持距离
...that you use your humor as a way to keep people at a distance.
我才刚认识你  我从没听说过你
I mean, I just met you. I don't know you from Adam.
独子对吧
Only child, right?
父母在你青春期前离婚
Parents divorced before you hit puberty.
-你怎会知道  -你很典型
- How did you know that? - It's textbook.
各位  你们都认识我爸吧
Hey, you guys. You all know my dad, right?
打算在纽约待多久
How long are you in the city?
就几天  我在市中心有工作
Just for a coupla days. I got a job midtown.
我想和我儿子同住
I'm better off staying with the kid...
总比来回坐渡轮折腾好
...than hauling my ass back and forth on the ferry.
-我没见过他  -他是我朋友罗杰
- I don't know this one. - This is my friend Roger.
-幸会  罗杰  -彼此彼此
- Good to meet you, Roger. - You too.
-玩布偶的那个怎么了  -爸
- What happened to the puppet guy? - Dad.
抱歉  罗斯  你的太太还好吗
Oh, excuse me. So, Ross, how's the wife?
一次不中是吧
0 for 2, huh?
钱德勒  快  说点好笑的
Chandler, quick, say something funny.
我得挂了  我也想你
I gotta go. Miss you too.
我爱你  但现在很晚了
I love you, but it's getting late
我打声招呼  妈妈好
Say hi. Hey, Ma.
听着  我和包西达大夫约了时间
Listen! I made the appointment with Dr.Bassida and
什么
Excuse me?
你知道这不是妈吗
Did you know this isn't Ma?
她叫罗妮
Her name's Ronni.
宠物殡葬业者
She's a pet mortician.
当然
Sure.
你和她在一起多久了...
So, how long you been...?
记得你小时候
Remember when you were a little kid,
我常带你去海军军港看大船吗
I'd take you to the navy yard and show you the big ships?
-从那时候就开始了  -不  才6年
- Since then? - No, it's only been six years.
我只想勾起你美好的回忆
I just wanted to put a nice memory in your head
让你觉得我并不一直是个大烂人
so you'd know that I wasn't always such a terrible guy. ...
乔伊  你爱过吗
Joe, you ever been in love?
-我不知道  -那就是没有
- I don't know. - Then you haven't.
-你的番茄烧焦了  -别想转移话题
- You're burning tomatoes. - You're one to talk.
乔伊  你老爸爱得无法自拔
Joe, your dad's in love big time.
最糟的是我同时爱着两个女人
And the worst part of it is, it's with two different women.
拜托你告诉我其中一个是妈
Oh, man! Please tell me one of them is Ma.
当然其中一个是你妈  你是怎么搞的
Of course one of them's Ma. What's the matter with you?
这就像你某天起床突然发现
It's like if you woke up one day and found out...
你爸过着双面人生
...your dad leads this double life.
就像是为中情局工作的间谍
He's like actually some spy working for the ClA.
那一定很酷
That'd be cool.
但这个很烂
This blows!
为何父母就不能是父母
I know. Why can't parents just stay parents?
为何他们就得成为人间男女  为何他们要
Why do they have to become people? Why do they have?
为什么...
Why...
...别再盯着我的胸部看
...can't you stop staring at my breasts?
什么
What?
那一天你还看得不够吗
Didn't you get a good enough look the other day?
我们都已是成年人
We're all adults here.
此事只有一个解决之道
There's only one way to resolve this.
既然你看过她的胸脯
Since you saw her boobies
你应该让她看你的小弟弟
I think you have to show her your pee-pee.
知道吗  我看这事没戏
You know, I don't see that happening.
拜托  他说得对  以牙还牙
Come on. He's right. Tit for tat.
我不会让你看我的"牙"的
Well, I'm not showing you my tat!
-是菲比  -还有罗杰
- It's Phoebe. - And Rog!
快上来
Come on up.
这下可好  罗杰来了
Oh, good! Rog is here.
-罗杰怎么了  -没什么  小事
- What's the matter with Rog? - It's a little thing.
我讨厌这家伙
I hate that guy!
他是有点太爱分析  这是他的工作
So he was a little analytical. That's what he does.
别这样  他没那么糟
Come on, he's not that bad.
这你就错了  如果当初我感觉到
You see that's where you're wrong! Why would I marry her...
她是女同志  我何必和她结婚呢
...if I thought in any level that she was a lesbian?
我不知道  或许你想让婚姻失败
I don't know. Maybe you wanted your marriage to fail.
为什么  我为什么  这样为什么
Why? Why would l? Why?
我不知道  或许自信心不足
I don't know. Maybe low self-esteem?
或许是总比你妹妹好所以有意弥补
Maybe to compensate for overshadowing a sibling.
-或许...  -等等  回到妹妹的话题
- Maybe - Wait! Go back to that "sibling" thing.
我说不准
Well, I don't know.
你可能有意破坏你的婚姻
You could've sabotaged your marriage...
让你妹在父母面前不那么失败
...so the sibling would feel like less of a failure as your parent.
这太荒谬了  她不争气关我什么事
That's ridiculous! I don't feel guilty for her failures.
-原来你认为我不争气  -他不错吧
- You think I'm a failure? - Isn't he good?
恩  不  我不是那个意思
Yeah. No, that's not what I was saying.
你知道吗  多年来我一直以为你支持我
Y'know, all these years, I thought you were on my side.
但或许你婚姻失败是为了讨好爸妈
But maybe what you were doing was sucking up to Mom and Dad
让他们更心疼你
so they'd keep liking you better!
我娶女同志是想让你建立自信
I married a lesbian to make you look good!
你说得对  我想你的确是对的
You're right. I mean, you're right.
那不仅是威宝玩具的问题
It wasn't just the Weebles,
而是威宝游乐宫
but the Weeble Play Palace...
和威宝游轮的问题
...and the Weeble's Cruise Ship...
它上面的救生艇让威宝能缓缓驶出
...with this lifeboat for the Weebles to wobble in.
那滋味不好受
That's tough, tough stuff.
来吧菲比  要看电影我们现在该走了
Come on Pheebs, we're gonna catch that movie, we gotta go.
打起精神来  瑞秋
Feel better. Rach.
菲比  我们快来不及了
We're gonna be late, sweetie.
-谢谢你做的一切  莫妮卡  -不客气
- Thanks for everything, Mon. - No problem.
各位  很高兴和各位再度见面
Listen, it was great seeing you again.
莫妮卡  饼干别吃太多
Mon, easy on those cookies, okay?
切记  那只是食物  不是爱
Remember, they're just food, they're not love.
我讨厌这家伙
I hate that guy!
晚安  各位
Good night, you guys.
看啊  这是我们订的女人
Oh, look. It's the woman we ordered.
需要帮忙吗
Hey, can we help you?
不用  谢谢  我在等乔伊·崔比安尼
No, thanks. I'm just waiting for Joey Tribbiani.
我就是乔伊·崔比安尼
I'm Joey Tribbiani.
不是你  是老乔伊  天啊
Oh, no, not you. Big Joey. Oh, my God!
你比照片上帅多了
You're so much cuter than your pictures.
我是罗妮
I'm Ronni.
想吃起司块吗
Cheese Nip?
乔伊患有"栓塞"  我来一块
Joey's having an embolism, but I'd go for a nip.
大部分人在宠物过世后
Most people, when their pets pass on...
希望它们躺平就像睡着一样
they want them laid out like they're sleeping.
但有时候有些人要他们摆出姿势
But, occasionally you get a person who wants them in a pose.
像追自己的尾巴
Like chasing their tail.
跳起接住飞盘
Or jumping to catch a Frisbee.
乔伊  如果我先走
Joey, if I go first,
我的姿势要像找钥匙一样
I wanna be looking for my keys.
-这姿势不错  -嗨
- That's a good one! - Hey.
嗨  爸爸  罗妮来了
Hey, Dad. Ronni's here.
-嗨  -嘿
- Hi. - Hey.
宝贝  你来干什么
Hello, babe! What are you doing here?
你的假发留在我的住处
Oh, you left your good hair at my place.
我想你明天会面用得上
I thought you'd need it tomorrow for your meet.
谢谢
Thank you.
谁想玩吸管弹珠游戏
So, who's up for a big game of Kerplunk?
听着  我不该来这儿的
Look, I shouldn't have come.
我该走了  我不想错过最后一班地铁
I better go. I'll miss the last train.
不  我不要你坐夜车
I don't want you taking that thing.
我要住哪儿  这吗
Where do I stay? Here?
我们去住饭店
We'll go to a hotel.
-不行  -不行
- No, you won't. - No, we won't.
你们去饭店就一定会办事
If you go to a hotel, you'll be doing stuff.
我要你们待在这儿  这样我就可以监视
I want you here so I can keep an eye on you.
-你要监视我们  -没错  先生
- You're gonna keep an eye on us? - Right. Mister.
我不管你多大年纪  只要住在我家
And I don't care how old you are, as long as you are under my roof...
—切就得听我的
...you're gonna live by my rules.
也就是不准你跟女友睡在一起
That means no sleeping with your girlfriend.
他好严格
Wow, he's strict.
爸  你睡我房间
Dad, you'll be in my room.
罗妮  你睡钱德勒的房间
Ronni. You can stay in Chandler's room.
谢谢  你真是个好孩子
Thanks. You're a good kid.
来  我带你去看我房间
Come on, I'll show you to my room.
感觉真奇怪  没听到人回答
That sounds weird not followed by,
"不  谢了  时候不早了"
"No, thanks, it's late."
只有今晚  明天你就得做出改变
This is just for tonight. Tomorrow you gotta change.
-你已经荒唐够久了  -什么改变
- This has gone on long enough. - What kind of change?
-和罗妮分手  -我不能
- Break up with Ronni - I can't do that.
不然就向妈自首  这样是不对的
Then come clean with Ma! This is not right!
-对  但是  -我不想听  快进我房里
- Yes, but... - I don't wanna hear it! Now go to my room!
别踢了
Hey, kickie!
-你在干什么  -找寻舒适的位置
- What are you doing? - Getting comfortable.
-穿着内裤我睡不着  -你非穿不可
- I can't sleep in my underwear. - Well, you're gonna.
我一直在想...
I was thinking about
我总看着女人一个接一个地来
how I'm always seeing girls on top of girls....
她们是首尾相接
Are they end-to-end,
还是像煎饼一样叠起来
or tall, like pancakes?
你懂我意思的
Y'know what I mean,
我总是跟很多女人出去约会
about how I'm always going out with all these women.
我总想着  当梦中情人出现时
I always figured, when the right one comes along...
我就会勇往直前  坚持到最后
I'd be able to be a stand-up guy and go the distance, y'know?
但如今看见我爸...我转念一想
Now I'm looking at my dad, thinking
你不是他  你是你自己
You're not him, you're you.
当全天下都希望你继承你爸的事业时
When they were all over you to go into your father's pipe-fitting business,
你有屈服吗
did you cave?
-没有  -没有
- No. - No.
你决心从事不稳定的演员事业
You chose the out-of-work-actor business.
这不是件容易的事  但你办到了
That wasn't easy, but you did it.
我也相信当你的梦中情人出现时
I believe when the right woman comes along...
你会有勇气对她说
...you'll have the courage and the guts to say,
"不  谢谢  我已婚"
"No, thanks, I'm married."
-你真的这样认为  -真的
- You really think so? - Yeah, I really do.
-谢谢  钱德勒  -滚开
- Thanks, Chandler. - Get off!
-嗨  -有事吗
- Hi. - Hi. May I help you?
乔伊说我能用你的浴室
Joey said I could use your shower
因为钱德勒正在用我们的
since Chandler's in ours.
好的  你是谁
Okay. Who are you?
我叫罗妮  罗妮·拉帕罗罗
Oh, I'm Ronni. Ronni Rapalono.
那个情妇
The mistress?
-请进  -谢谢
- Come on in. - Thanks.
我叫瑞秋  浴室在那儿
I'm Rachel. Bathroom's there.
罗妮  钱德勒进浴室多久了
Ronni, how long has Chandler been in the shower?
也就5分钟
Oh, like five minutes.
太好了
Perfect.
请系好安全带,
Fasten your seat belts,
"参观小弟弟"时间到了
it's pee-pee time.
-嗨  崔先生  -早安  亲爱的
- Hey, Mr. Trib. - Hey, good morning, dear.
钱德勒·宾  该我看你的小弟弟了
Chandler Bing, it's time to see your thing.
-你抽什么风  -我以为你是钱德勒
- What's the matter with you? - I thought it was Chandler!
你应该在浴室  好让我看见你的小弟弟
You were supposed to be in there so I'd see your thing!
抱歉  我的小弟弟和我在那儿
Sorry, my thing was in there with me.
-如何  -不错
- How's it going? - Good.
罗杰想办次晚宴
Roger's having a dinner thing.
他叫我邀请你们
He wanted me to invite you guys.
-怎么了  -没事
- So, what's going on? - Nothing.
只是...
It's just....
罗杰  我说不上来
It's Roger, you know?
有些事...
There's something about
基本上我们认为他...
Basically we just feel that he's....
-我们讨厌那家伙  -我们讨厌他...
- We hate that guy! - We hate him!
-菲比  我们很抱歉  -没事
- We're sorry, Pheebs. - Okay.
你们不觉得是因为他太观察入微
Don't you think it's just that he's so perceptive...
吓到你们了吗
...it freaked you out?
不  我们讨厌他...
No, we hate him!
抱歉
I'm sorry.
妈  你来干什么
Ma! What are you doing here?
我拿这个来给你  还有这个
I came to give you this and this!
好大的戒指
Big ring!
你为什么要对你爸讲一大堆
Why'd you fill your father's head with garbage...
关于改正的废话呢
...about making things right?
何不顺其自然呢
Things were fine this way!
里面有鸡肉  拿去放好
There's chicken in there. Put it away.
拜托  乔依  真的
For God's sake, Joey! Really.
慢着  你都知道
Hold on. You knew?
我当然知道  你认为呢
Of course I knew. What do you think?
你爸又不是詹姆士·邦德[007]
Your father is no James Bond.
你得听听他都用什么烂借口
You should've heard a couple of his stories.
"我在会计这儿睡"
"I'm sleeping over at my accountant's."
-什么借口啊  拜托  -那你怎能...
- What is that? Please! - So then, how could you?
记得你爸以前的样子吗
Do you remember how your father used to be?
总是大吼大叫  总是不开心
Always yelling. Nothing made him happy.
连木材店和瓶中船也无法让他开心
Not that wood shop, not those stupid little ships in the bottle.
现在他很开心
Now he's happy.
这样很好  他总算有个嗜好
I mean, it's nice. He has a hobby.
妈  恕我直言
Ma, I don't mean to be disrespectful...
你到底在说什么
... but what the hell are you talking about?
-我是说  那你怎么办  -我很好啊
- I mean, what about you? - Me? I'm fine.
听着  宝贝  在理想的世界中
Look, honey, in an ideal world...
既没有她  而且你爸也长得和斯汀一样帅
...there'd be no her and your father would look like Sting.
我再跟你说件事
And I'll tell you something else:
自从那个"卷毛狗"出现后
Ever since that poodle-stuffer came along...
他感到极其内疚而开始对我体贴
... he's so ashamed of himself that he's been more attentive.
他跟我恩爱许多  每天都像结婚纪念日
He's been more loving. It's like every day is our anniversary.
-那我该为你高兴  -不需要
- I'm happy for you? - Well, don't be!
因为现在全搞砸了
Now everything's screwed up.
我只想回到从前
I just want it the way it was.
妈  对不起
Ma, I'm sorry.
我只是以为你会想要知道
I just did what I thought you'd want.
我知道  亲爱的  我知道
I know you did, cookie. I know you did.
告诉我  你看见她没
So tell me. Did you see her?
看到了
Yeah.
-你比她漂亮十倍都不止  -嘴巴真甜
- You're 10 times prettier than she is. - That's sweet.
我斗得过她吗
Could I take her?
你有这戒指  她斗不过的
With this ring, no contest.
-怎么了  亲爱的  -没事
- What's wrong, sweetie? - Nothing.
-到底怎么了  快说嘛  -好吧
- No, what's wrong? Come on. - Okay.
我没事  问题出在我朋友身上
It's nothing. I'm fine. It's just It's my friends.
他们对你有意见
They have a liking problem with you...
他们不能...
...in that they don't.
他们不能怎么
They don't?
他们不像我一样能看见你的好处
But they don't see all the wonderfulness that I see.
他们看不见你美好和体贴的一面
They don't see all the good and sweet stuff.
-他们认为你有点...  -什么
- They think you're a little - What?
紧张和令人发毛
Intense and creepy.
但我菲比不这么认为
But I don't. Me, Phoebe.
我对他们的反应毫不感到惊讶
I'm not at all surprised about that.
是吗  看  这就是我欣赏你的地方
You're not? See, that's why you're so great!
当群体动力失调时
Actually it's quite typical behavior...
这是很典型的反应
...when you have this kind of dysfunctional group dynamic.
这种相互依赖  情绪激动
You know, this kind of codependent, emotionally stunted...
坐在那家傻兮兮的咖啡屋
...sitting in your stupid coffeehouse,
拿着又大又蠢的咖啡杯
with your stupid big cups...
或许还有乳头在上面
...which might as well have nipples on them.
你们全都想着"说说我是怎样的人"
And you're all like, "Oh, define me! Define me!
"爱我  我需要爱"
Love me! I need love!
你和你爸谈过了
You talked to your dad?
他要以我妈希望的方式继续欺骗我妈
He's gonna keep cheating on Ma like she wanted.
我妈要继续假装她一无所知
Ma will keep pretending she doesn't know.
我妹蒂娜不能再见她丈夫
And my sister, Tina, can't see her husband.
因为他接到禁制令
He got a restraining order.
这两件事没关系  但我今天才听说
Which has nothing to do with it. I found out today.
沃顿山[电视剧]这两天发生了很多变故啊
Things have changed here on Waltons'mountain.
-乔伊  你没事吧  -或许吧
-So, Joey, are you okay? - Yeah, I guess.
他们是...父母
It's just You know,they're parents.
到了时候  你只能顺其自然
After a certain point, you gotta let go.
就算你更有见识  还是得让他们自己去犯错
Even if you know better, you gotta let them make their own mistakes.
想想看  再过几年  我们就会变成他们
And think, in a few years, we'll turn into them.
拜托
Oh, please.
如果我像他们一样
If I turn into my parents,
我不是变成倒追金发小帅哥的酒鬼
I'll be an alcoholic blond chasing 20 year's old boys...
就是变得和我妈一样
...or I'll end up like my mom!
-嗨  -嗨  菲比
- Hey. - Hey, Pheebs.
怎么样
How's it going?
还好  只是我和罗杰分手了
Okay, except I broke up with Roger.
-我就知道  -不...真的
- Yeah, right. - No, no, really.
-怎么了  -我说不上来
- What happened? - I don't know. I mean...
他是个好人而且对我很体贴
... he's a good person, and he can be really sweet.
从某些方面来讲  他很适合我
In some ways, I think he is so right for me.
只是...我讨厌这个人
It's just.... I hate that guy!
嗨  乔伊  怎么了
Hi, Joey. What's going on?
为胸脯偿债特快列车清理轨道
Clear the tracks for the boobie payback express.
下一站  瑞秋·格林
Next stop, Rachel Greene.
乔伊  你在干什么
Joey, what the hell were you doing?
对不起  看错胸脯了
Sorry, wrong boobies!
好啊  乔伊
Hello, Joey!
好啊  亲爱的
Hello, dear!